Guide to the Leon Kolb collection of Portraits: engravings, etchings, mezzotinits, lithographs, and acquatints, M0871
Stanford University. Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 1. Accn 1972-002, 12.0 Linear feet 1647 items (prints)
  - 0671. Honthorst, Cerrit van, 1590-1656 (Flat-box 5, Folder 12)
    Gerardus Honthorst./Hagaa Comitis Pictor Rumanarum Figurarum Maioru.!Ant.van Dyck pinxit. Paul du Pont sculp. Cum privilegio. Half-portrait in oblong looking left. Engraving. 23.6 x 16.9 cm. Singer No. 14066/41044. Dutuit No. 58.7a. Mauquoy-H. No. 52.VIII. From: Iconography of Vandyka.
  - 0672. Hoofs (Hofdius], Pieter Cornelisz, 1581-1647 (Flat-box 5, Folder 12)
    Mr Hanrik Hoofs,/Burgemeaster en Read dar Stad Amsterdam./J.Houbraken facit nat Schildery by den Wal Ed: Gestr: Haer Henrik Hooft Danielsz, Burgemeester der Stad Mister dam. Bust in oval looking left surrounded by oblong. Engraving. 18.2 x 12.2 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 0673. Hooper, John, bp. of Gloucester, 1495-1555 (Flat-box 5, Folder 12)
    Joannes Hooperus./ Episc.s Clocest & Vigorn.s Martirio Coronatus Ao Dni 1555/Printed for H.Parker & E.Bakewell in Cornhill London./R.Houston facit. Bust In oval looking right. Mezzotint. 26.4 x 20.1 cm.
  - 0674. Hoornbeeck, Jan, 1617-1666 (Flat-box 5, Folder 12)
    Johannes Hoornbeeck./S,Theol. Doctor. In Ecclesia & Accademia Ultraiectina/Pastor atq. Professor./Aatatis 34. Anno 1651. J.Smyderhoef sculps. Pieter Goos excudit. Half-portrait in oblong looking left. Engraving. Plate-mark trimmed off. Singer No. 14092/41102.
  - 0675. Hopton, Ralph, Baron, 1598-1652 (Flat-box 5, Folder 12)
    Ralph, Lord Hopton./Ob. 1652./From the original of Vandyke, in the collection of! The Right Hon.ble The Earl of Egremont./Engraved by T.A.Dean./London. Published August 1. 1827 by Harding & Lepard Pall Mall East. Knee-piece in oblong looking right. Photo-engraving. 24.9 x 18.4 cm. Pasted on cardboard with plate-mark.
  - 0676. Home, Richard Henry, 1803-1884 (Flat-box 5, Folder 12)
    [Horne]. Unframed seated portrait looking left. Lithograph. 37.6 x 32.7 cm.
  - 0677. Home-Took, 1736-1812 (Flat-box 5, Folder 12)
    John Horne Tooke,/Volksredner/1798./Fr.Bolt sc. 1798. Bust in oval looking left. Stipple-engraving. 16.0 x 10.0 cm. Singer No. 14152/41244.
  - 0678. Hugues, Capat, king of France, 938-996 (Flat-box 5, Folder 12)
    Hugh Capat./J.Chapman sculpsit./London Published as the Act directs. Feb.l.l801. by J.Wilkas. Right profile in oval. Wall with axecutional squadron in oblong below. Stipple-engraving. 16.2 x 11.3 cm.
  - 0679. Huijgens [Huijgens], Constantin, 1596-1687 (Flat-box 5, Folder 12)
    D.Constantinus Hugens Eques./Toparcha Svylecom./Paul Pontius sculp. Ant.van Dyck pinxit. cum privilagio. Half-portrait in oblong looking slightly left. Engraving. 24.9 x 17.4 cm. Singer No. 14445/42017. Dutuit No. 59.3e. Mauquoy-H. No. 53.VI. From: Iconography of Vandyke.
  - 0680. Hunnius, Aegidius, 1550-1603 (Flat-box 5, Folder 12)
    D.Aegidius Hunnius, In Academicis Marpurg. per XVI. at Witeberg. Par XI. Annos Theol. Prof. Elect. Sax. Suparint. Gen. & Consistassessor./Nat. Winendae WUrtenb. A. 1550. Denat. Witabargae Sax./l6O3. Joh.Chr.B~cklin Sculp. Bust in lettered oval looking right. Eulogy of four lines by Io.Henr.Feustkingius D.II on base. Engraving. 31.9 x 11.8 cm. Singer No. 14397/41847.
  - 0681. Hus, Johannes, 1369?-1415 (Flat-box 6, Folder 1)
    Johannes Hus, Martyr/2d May.s Ao. 1415 Combustus Mortem Obijt./printed for H.Parkar & E.Bakewell in Cornhill London./R.Houston fecit. Right profile in oval. Mezzotint. 26.1 x 20.1 cm.
  - 0682. Hyde, Anne, duchess of York, 1637-1671 (Flat-box 6, Folder 1)
    Anne Hyde Duchess of York./From the original of Sir Peter Lely, in the Collection of/The Right Hon.ble. The Earl of Clarendon./Drawn by H.Crease, & Engraved (with Permi-ssion) by J.S.Agar./London. Published June 1. 1815. by Lackington, Allen & Co. and Longman, Hurst, Raes, Orme & Brown. Bust in oblong looking right. Stipple-engraving. 36.4 x 25.8 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 0683. Innocantius X, [Giovanni Battista Panf iii], 1574-1655 (Flat-box 6, Folder 1)
    Innocent the Tenth./In the Cabinet at Houghton./Velasco (sic) pinxit./G.Farington del./J.Boydell axcudit 1774./Val Green fecit./Published 1774 by John Boydall engraver of the Cheapside, London. Bust looking right. Text under coat of arms: "Fan quaa sentiat.” Mezzotint. 15.0 x 10.0 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 0684. Ireton, Henry, 1611-1651 (Flat-box 6, Folder 1)
    Henry Ireton Comissary Gen.l./and Lord Deputy of Ireland.!from an Original painting. M.V.de Gucht fecit. Half-portrait in oval looking right. Engraving. 17.4 x 10.0 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 0685. Ireton, Henry, 1611-1651 (Flat-box 6, Folder 1)
    General Ireton./In the Possession of David Pothill Esq./Coopar pinxit./J.Houbrakan sculps. Mist. l74l./Impensis I. & P. Knapton Londini, 1742. Bust in lettered oval looking slightly left surrounded by symbolic Baroque composition. Engraving. 37.5 x 23.7 cm. Singer No. 14590/92510. From: Birch T., The Heads of the Most Illustrious Persons of Great Britain, J. Knapton, London 1743.
  - 0686. Ireton, Henry, 1611-1651 (Flat-box 6, Folder 1)
  - 0687. Isabella, Clara Eugenia, archduchess of Austria, Regent of the Netherlands, 1566-1633 (Flat-box 6, Folder 1)
    Serenissima D.Isabella. Clara Eugenia. Hispaniarum Infans atc./Sar.mi.Albarti. Archid. Austriae, Ducis Burgundiae Belgarum Prlncipis Etc. /Vidua, Mater Castromum./D.A. van Dyck Eques pinxit. Cu Pnivileg. Vomsterman sculp. Knee-piece in oblong looking might. Etching. 24.7 xl5.6 cm. Singer No. 14615/42571. Dutuit No. ll8.4a. Mauquoy-H. No. l16.IV•. From: Iconography of Vandyke.
  - 0688. Isabella, Clara Eugenia, archduchess of Austria, Regent of the Netherlands, 1566-1633 (Flat-box 6, Folder 1)
    Isabella Clara Euge. Hispan. Inf. Duciss, Burgun. Brab. Comit. Fland.Hannon Art.! Isabella Clara Eugenia Infante van/Spaignon Hertoginn.o van Borgundion/Brabant etc. Gravinne van Vlaenderen./Hog-gou Artoys. etc. N. de Clerk exc. Bust in lettered oval looking left. Engraving. 19.2 x 12.4 cm.
  - 0689. Isabella [Elizabeth of Bourbon], Queen of [Felipe IV] Spain, 1602-1644 (Flat-box 6, Folder 1)
    D. Elisabathae Borboniae Principi/Serenissimmae D.Philippi in Hispaniarum/Indiarumq Regis Incomparabili. Bust in oval looking right. Engraving. 15.3 x 11.2 cm. Singer No. 14631/42628.
  - 0690. James I, king of England, 1566-1625 (Flat-box 6, Folder 1)
    lacobus D.G. Magnae Britanniae Franciaa at Hibemniae Rex. lEn tibi, Rex., supra, cum Pallade, doctus Apollo,/In Laudes manito; Magne lacobe, tuas:/Infr~ ta posita est Pax alma et Copia rerun, /Quam felix populus, Magma Jacobe, tuus./Pet.Iselb. excud. Bust in lettered oval looking right. Engraving. 19.9 x 12.7 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 0691. James I, king of England, 1566-1625 (Flat-box 6, Folder 2)
    Jacobus de Eersten,/Koning von Engeland &c./B.Picart sculp. dim. 1728. Bust in oval looking right. Engraving. 25.4 x 17.6 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off. Singer No. 14760/42987.
  - 0692. James I, king of England, 1566-1625 (Flat-box 6, Folder 2)
    Jacobus D.C. Angliae, Franciae, Schotiae, at Hiberniaa Rex atc./Ioan Meyssens excudit Anverpiae. Half-portrait looking right. Engraving. 17.2 x 11.2 cm.
  - 0693. James I, king of England, 1566-1625 (Flat-box 6, Folder 2)
    Semenissinus Iacobus VI Del Gratia Scotorum Orcad Rex./Quod sis, esse velis./Afra lubam tellus, Cotyn effert Thnacia, doctos/Reges; ingenium Scotica terra tuum. Bust in lettered oval looking left. Eneravine. 16.4 x 11.8 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0694. James I, king of England, 1566-1625 (Flat-box 6, Folder 2)
    Potentiss. Jacobus D.G. Magnaa Britan. Galliae at Hibern. Rex Fidel Defensor. Bust looking slightly right in lettered oval. On baroque ribbons "Regna Iacobus,I Gentem unam./Faciam eos in/Hennicus Rosas”. "Beati pacifici.”/”Youth not myne anoynted.’ "Hony soit qui/mal y panse.”/”The right sign. and most might/tie Monarch lames by the Gra/ce of God of Great Bnitaine, Fraun/ce and Ireland & Defendor of the Faith. Engraving. 21.7 x 14.0 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 0695. James I, king of Great Britain, 1566-1625 (Flat-box 6, Folder 2)
    James 1:/King of Great Britain/Franca and Ireland,/Defender of the Faith &c/Paulus Vansomer p. G.Vertue sculp./An Original Painting in the Palace of Hampton Court. Bust looking to the right. Rectangle ornate frame topped with crown and three coat of arms. Ribbon floating under them inscribed: "Beati pacifici.” Orb and sceptre at lower left, with ribbon inscribed: "Regere, Impenio, Populos.” Engraving. 30.0 x 19.5 cm. Slightly stained on right lower corner. Trimmed close to plate-mark. From: Birch, T., The Heads of the Most Illustrious Persons of Great Britain, J.Knapton, London 1756.
  - 0696. James II, king of England, 1633-1701 (Flat-box 6, Folder 2)
    Item missing. Jacques II, Roy/d’Angleterre/Wandam Warff pinxit. J.Audran scuipsit. Bust in oval looking left with battle scene below. Engraving. 30.0 x 17.2 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0697. James II, king of England, 1633-1701 (Flat-box 6, Folder 2)
    K. James the 2d./Drawn and engraved by Geo.Vertue from an Original Painting done for Secretary Pepys, and painted/from the Life by Sr.Godfrey Kneller Ano. Dni. 1688. Bust in wreath with Papal crown over, and broken anchors under it. Engraving. 30.6 x 19.7 cm. From: Birch, T., The Heads of the Most Illustrious Persons of Great Britain, J.Knapton, London, 1756.
  - 0698. James II, king of England, 1633-1701 (Flat-box 6, Folder 2)
    James 2 by the Grace of God King/of England, Scotland, Franca, and Ireland etc:/ Defender of the Faith./ex Formis Nicolal Vischer. Cum Privil: Ordin: General Belgij Foaderati. /P.Schenk f. Bust in oval looking slightly left. Mezzotint. 19.3 x 13.5 cm. Singer No.14761/43040.
  - 0699. James II, king of England, 1633-1701 (Flat-box 6, Folder 2)
    Jacques II. Roy d’Angleterre./Wander Warf pinxit.!J.Audran sculpsit. Bust im oval looking right over small picture of fugitive king. Engraving. 29.9 x 17.3 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off. Singer No. 14761/43031.
  - 0700. Jamasone, George, 1587?-1644 (Flat-box 6, Folder 2)
    George Jamesone./Bannerman Sculp. Bust in oblong looking left. Engraving. 17.8 x 13.8 cm.
  - 0701. Jan III, [Sobieski], king of Poland, 1624-1696 (Flat-box 6, Folder 3)
    John Sobieski./Engraved by J.Thomson from an original Picture in the Gallery of the Louvre,/William Mackenzie, Glasgow, Edinburgh, London & New York. Half-portrait in oblong looking right. Stipple-engraving. 27.5 x 18.3 cm.
  - 0702. Jane Seymour, queen of England, 1509-1537 (Flat-box 6, Folder 3)
    Jane Seymour Queen of Henry VII./Impansis J. & P.Knapton, Londini 1746. Bust looking left in lettered oval surrounded by symbolic composition. Engraving. 36.8 x 22.7 cm.
  - 0703. Jansen, Cornelis, bp. of Yjperen, 1585-1638 (Flat-box 6, Folder 3)
    Cornelius Jansan/T.Chambers sculp. Bust in oblong looking left. Engraving. 17.3 x 13.1 cm.
  - 0704. Jean II, king of France, 1409-1476 (Flat-box 6, Folder 3)
    John II. of France./J.Chapman sculpsit. London./Published by the Act directs Decr. 7th 1805 by J.Wilkes. Right profile in oval. Two equestrians preceded by trumpeters and followed by flag-bearers in oblong below. Stipple-engraving. 16.2 x 11.3 cm.
  - 0705. Jeannin, de Montjoye, Pierre, 1540-1623 (Flat-box 6, Folder 3)
    Messire Pierre Jeannin premier President/au Parlemant de Bourgogne, Surintendant/ des Finances, Ministre d’Estat &c./Nanteuil faciebat. Bust in oval looking right. Engraving. 28.0 x 18.5 cm. Singer No. 14848/43301. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0706. Jeannin, de Montjoye Pierre, 1540-1623 (Flat-box 6, Folder 3)
    Le President Jeannin./Jac.Lubin sculp. Bust in oval looking left framed by oblong. Engraving. 25.3 x 19.3 cm. Singer No. 14848/43302. Copy of former portrait.
  - 0707. Joannas de Burgundia, [Jean sans Paun], 1371-1419 (Flat-box 6, Folder 3)
    Joannes Digtus Intrepidus/Dux Burgundiae, Comes Flan/driae at Arthesiae etc. Poten/ tissimus at Serenissinus./Pet. de lode excudit. Bust looking slightly right in half-round arch framed by oblong. Engraving. 17.6 x 12.6 cm.
  - 0708. Jode, Petrus de, 1570-1634 (Flat-box 6, Folder 3)
    Petrus de lode/Calcographus Et Delineator Antvarpiensis./Ant.van Dyck pinxit. Vorstertnan sculpsit. Cum privilegio. Half-portrait in oblong looking right. Engraving. 25.3 x 17.2 cm. Singer No. 14940/43625. Dutuit No. 9l.5e. Mauquoy-H. No. 84.111. From: Iconography of Vandyke.
  - 0709. Joda, Petrus de, 1570-1634 (Flat-box 6, Folder 3)
    Patrus de Iode,/A astd tres bon engraveur, at desaigneur tres illustra: ii a faict plusieurs/chafs des oeuvra il a long temps demeura a Rome, at en l’an 1601 retoumnoit/en Anvers, villa de sa naisance, aijant eu pour maistre Henri Goltz. ii mourut l’an 1634. le 9 d’auoust./M.Ferdinand pinxit. F.de lode Junior sculpsit.Io.Meyssens excudit. Bust in oblong looking left. Engraving. 16.4 x 10.5 cm. Singer No. 14940/43627. From: Meyssans, J., The true Effigies of the most eminent Painters...that have flourished in Europa.. .Engraven, [Anvers] 1694.
  - 0710. Jode, Petnus de, the Younger, 1606-1674 (Flat-box 6, Folder 3)
    Petrus da lode. Iunior/Chalcographus Antverpiae./Ant.van Dyck pinxit.fPetrus de lode sculpsit. Knee-piece in oblong looking right. Engraving. 26.3 x 18.3 cm. Singer No. 14941/43635. Dutult No. lO6.4e. Mauquoy-H. No. l04.V. ‘From: Iconography of Vandyke.
  - 0711. Joda, Petrus de, the Younger, 1606-1674 (Flat-box 6, Folder 4)
    Petrus da Iode./Le ieusne, natif d’Axivers en lan 1606, la 22me de novembre il a apr~ chaz son pare, at ii ast devanu un gravaur fort delicat, ii a eta avac son/pare quelque temps a Paris, pour engraveur qualques pieces pour Mons. Bon/enfant at Sr.L’Imago.on trouve plusiers de ses estampas en lumiera. ii se tient an Anvers./Th. Willeborts pinxit. Patr. da lode sculpsit. Io.Meyssens escudit. Bust in oblong looking left. Engraving. 16.6 x 11.6 cm. Singer No. 14941/43633. From: Meyssans J.,The true Effigies of the most eminent Paintars...that have flourished in Europe... Engraven. [Anvers] ,l694.
  - 0712. Joachem, Christian Gottlieb, 1694-1758 (Flat-box 6, Folder 4)
    Christianus Gottliab/Ioecherus/S.Theol. D.Historiarus in Academia Lipsensi/P.P.0. Majoris Proncip. Collegij Collegiatus/et Academiae Bibliothecanius/Nat.d. 29.iul. A.S.R. 1694./Dec. III./I.I.Haid sculps./et excud./Aug.Vind. Half-portrait in oblongish Baroque frame looking right. Mezzotint. 3l.o x 19.0 cm. Singer No. 14944/43641.
  - 0713. Joerger, count von Tollet, Johann Septimus, 1594-1653 (Flat-box 6, Folder 4)
    Joannes Saptimus J6rger S.Rom.Imp. Comes, Dominus in Toilet at Gezerstorf, Liber Bar3 a Craisbach, Supremus Haareditarius Aulae Magister Austniae Super. Bust looking slightly left in lettered oval. Mars and Hermes, cherubs in backgrc~x Arms of war in foreground. In cartouche:”Jörgeri faciem Pallas depingit in area/Dun felix calamo consociat giadlum/Martis at Antis amans, Laudes superavit avonii!Gioria mara win nascia. mortis emit. G.P.H.” G.Strauch del. I.Sanders sculpsit. Engraving. 22.5 x 17.1 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 0714. Johann IX Philipp, archbishop and elector of Trier, 1735?-1768 (Flat-box 6, Folder 4)
    Joannes Philippus./S.Sedis Moguntiae Archiapiscopus S.R. Imperij/Per Gemmaniam Archicancellarius Pninceps Elector, nec/non Episcopus Harbipolensis, at Onientalis Franconiae Dux.!Anselmus van Hulle Deelin./Petr de Jode sculpsit. Bust in oval looking left. Engraving. 34.3 x 25.3 cm. No. 9 from Hulla, A. van, Pacificatoras orbis Christiani.. .Rotterdam,1697.
  - 0715. Johann, Braubach von, Landgrave of Hessen-Darnstadt, 1609-1651 (Flat-box 6, Folder 4)
    Illustnissimo at Cessissimo Principi ac Domino, Domino/Johanni Hassiae Langravio, Comiti in Cattimeliboco/Dietz, Zigenheim at Nidda, at Principi ac Domino/suo Clemantissimo: humilime ac devotissime/dedicat, consecrat, Sebastianus Furc, Chalcogr. Bust in oval looking slightly right. Etching. 27.0 x 16.0 cm. Trimmed close to plate mark.
  - 0716. John, Lackland, king of England, 1166-1216 (Flat-box 6, Folder 4)
    Johannes Rex Angl./Dns Hib./G.Vertue d. at Sculp. Bust in oval looking left in other oblong. Engraving. 28.9 x 19.2 cm. Singer No. 15110/45062. From: Birch, T., The Heads of the Most Illustrious Persons of Great Britain, London, 1756.
  - 0717. John, Lackland, king of England, 1166-1216 (Flat-box 6, Folder 4)
    The Monument of King John/in ye Cathedral Church of Worcester./Gravelot del. Du Bosc fecit. King on catafalqua, head at might. ‘The Monument of King John’ on ribbon, "Magma Charta” on scroll below. Engraving. 36.8 x 22.8 cm.
  - 0718. John of Gaunt, duke of Lancaster, 1340-1399 (Flat-box 6, Folder 4)
    John of Gaunt. King of Castila & Leon/Duke of Lancaster. /Paintad on Glass in an Antient Window in ye Library of All Souls Coil. Oxon. G.Vartue del & Sculp. Bust in Gothic opening looking left. Engraving. 29.0 x 18.9 cm. From: Bimch, T., The Heads of the Most Illustrious Persons of Great Britain, London, 1756.
  - 0719. Jones, Inigo, 1573-1652 (Flat-box 6, Folder 4)
    Inigo Jones./A.Bannemman sculp. Bust in oval looking left. Engraving. 18.5 x 14.4 cm.
  - 0720. Jones, Inigo, 1573-1652 (Flat-box 6, Folder 4)
    Celeberrimus Vir Inigo lones Praefectus Architecturae/Magnae Brittaniae Regis Etc.! Ant.van Dyck pinxit. R.V.Vorst sculp. Cum privileglo. Half portrait in oblong looking left. Paper in his left hand hanging into text. Engraving. 24.4 x 17.6 cm. Singer No. 15140/45129. Dutujt No. 79.5e. Mauquoy-H. No. 72.VII. From: Iconography of Vandyke.
  - 0721. Jones, Inigo, 1573-1652 (Flat-box 6, Folder 5)
    Inigo Jones./Painted by Vandyke./Engraved by R.Earlom, Published Sept. 2d by Boydell & Co. Cheapside, London. Bust looking right. Plain oval frame in rectangle. Mezzotint. 18.0 x 13.0 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 0722. Jones, Inigo, 1573-1652 (Flat-box 6, Folder 5)
    Inigo Jones./In the Common Parlour at Houghton./Size of the picture 1.8 5/8 by 2.1 in height./Van Dyke pinxit./G.Farington delin.t./Val.Green engraver/to his Majesty fecit Published Novr.l.1773 by Ino.Boydell engraver in Cheapside London. Bust in oval looking right. Mezzotint. 17.5 x 12.7 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark. Singer No. 15140/45132.
  - 0723. Jones, Sir William, 1746-1794 (Flat-box 6, Folder 5)
    Sir William Jones Knt./Aetatis 47/Drawn by A.W.Devis Calcutta./Engraved by Evans.! London. Published June 1. 1804. by John Hatchard, Picadilly. Bust in oblong looking slightly right. Lithograph. 29.0 x 20.3 cm.
  - 0724. Jonson, van Ceulen, Cornelis I, 1593-1661 (Flat-box 6, Folder 5)
    Cornelius Janssens./PaIntre tres excellent en grandes et petites ordonnances mais une lustre de portraicts/avec un admirable entendement la ville d’Amstelredam a le bonheur de jouir de sa/persone il a demeure long temps en Angleterre ou ii a faict plusieurs belles et admirables/pieces pour le Roij et plusieurs autres grandes Seigneurs./Corn.Janssens pinxIt. Coenr.Wouinans sculp. Io.Meyssens exc. Half-portrait in oblong looking left. Engraving. 16.1 x 11.4 cm. Singer No. 15147/45157. From: Meyssens, J., The true Effigies of the most eminent Painters...that have¬flourished in Europe....Engraven, [Anvers], 1694
  - 0725. Jonson, van Ceulen,Cornelis I, 1593-1661 (Flat-box 6, Folder 5)
    Cornelius Jansen./T.Chambars sculp. Bust in oblong looking left. Stipple-engraving. 16.6 x 12.6 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off. Mended in center. From: Walpole, H., Earl of Orford, Anecdotes of Painting, London, 1782.
  - 0726. Jordaens, Jacob, 1594-1678 (Flat-box 6, Folder 5)
    Iaecques Iordaens./Excellent peinctre en grand, faict connoistre son esprit relevé par sa belle manière de peindre,/est inventif en toute sorte d’ordonnances, soit en poésie, histoires, en devotion et d’autres, ii a faict/les belles choses racourtantes pour le Roy de Suede, et plusieurs autres princes et Seigneurs,/est né a Anvers lan 1594. le 19. de May, a faict son apprentisage chez son beaupere Adam van/Dort, tenant sa demeure en la ville de sa naissance./IaJordaens pinxit. Pet.de lode scuipsit. Ia. Meyssens excudit. Bust in oblong looking slightly left. Engraving. 16.8 x 11.4 cm. Singer No. 15152/45168. From: Meyssens, J., The true Effigies of the most eninent Painters.. .that have flourished in Europe.. .Engraven, [Anvers], 1694.
  - 0727. Jordaens, Jacob, 1594-1678 (Flat-box 6, Folder 5)
    lacobus Iordaens/Pictor Antverpiae, Humanoruni, Figurarum in Maioribus./Ant.van Dyck pinxit Pet.de lode sculp./Cum privilegio. Knee-piece in oblong looking slightly left. Engraving. 24.4 x 17.4 cm. Singer No. 15152/45165. Dutuit No. 40.4e. Mauquoy-H. No. 33.VI. From: Iconography of Vandyke.
  - 0728. Jordan, Dorothy, 1762-1816 (Flat-box 6, Folder 5)
    Mrs. Jordan./Eng. by R.Page. Bust in oval looking right. Stipple-engraving. 15.0 x 11.6 cm. Badly trimmed.
  - 0729. Juan, d'Austria, of Spain, viceroy of Aragon, 1629-1679 (Flat-box 6, Folder 5)
    Joannes Austriacus/Philippi. IV. Regis, Catholicic/Filius & a. Bust in oblong looking right, surrounded by Baroque composition. Engraving. 34.0 x 24.8 cm. No. 8 from unidentified series.
  - 0730. Julianus Apostata, Caesar Flavius Claudius J.Augustus, 44th emperor of Rome, 332-363 (Flat-box 6, Folder 5)
    The Emperor Julian II. (The Apostate.)/P.Dujardin eng./Gebbie & Co. Right profile without frame. Photo-engraving. 36.5 x 26.6 cm. Torn from book, foxed.
  - 0731. Julianus Didius, 20th emperor of Rome, 7-193 A.D. (Flat-box 6, Folder 6)
    The Emperor Didius Julianus./P.Dujardin eng./Gebbie & Co. Unfraned right profile. Photo-engraving. 36.5 x 26.7 cm. Torn from book, foxed.
  - 0732. Julius II, Giuliano della Rovere, 1443-1513 (Flat-box 6, Folder 6)
    Jules II.,/De la Galerie du Palais Royal./Ecole Romaine./Peint par, Raphael Sanzio d’Urbin. Grave par Morel. Seated knee-piece in oblong looking left. 10 lines of descriptive biographical text below. Engraving. 39.5 x 25.5 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0733. Jungen, Johann Maximilian, 1596-1649 (Flat-box 6, Folder 6)
    Nobiliss D. Joh.Maximil. zum Jungen/ Cos. Reip. Ffurt humil. off./H.d.B./Obiit 1638 Aeta 75/.Sebast.Furch ad vivu sculpsit. Bust in decorated oval looking right. Double quatrain of eulogy under oval. Engraving. 13.6 x 9.7 cm.
  - 0734. Kallenberg, Gerard, 17th cent. (Flat-box 6, Folder 6)
    Gerard Kallenberg./Luitenant-Admiraal/van Holland en Westfriesland./A.Schouman del. naar het Origineel van J.Vollerens by de Hr.Baartman. J.Houbraken fec./Js.Tirion excudit. Bust In oval looking left, framed by oblong. Engraving. 18.3 x 11.7 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 0735. Karl I, Herzog von Braunschweig-Luneburg-Bevern-Wolfenbuttel, 1713-1780 (Flat-box 6, Folder 6)
    Item missing. Charles Duc Regmant de Brunswick et de Lunebourg:/Dédié a son Altesse Serenissime./ Par son trés humble et trés obeissant Serviteur De Marcenay de Ghuy./La Fontaine del. De Marcenay sculp. Knee-piece in oblong looking left. Engraving. 36.0 x 24.7 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off. Singer No. 15480/46380.
  - 0736. Karl V, emperor of Germany, 1500-1558 (Flat-box 6, Folder 6)
    Portrait de Charles-Quint./Peint par Vandyck. Dessin~ par J.B.Wicar. Grave a Rome par H.Guttenberg. Equestrian portrait looking left. Engraving. 24.3 x 16.9 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0737. Karl V, emperor of Germany, 1500-1558 (Flat-box 6, Folder 6)
    The Emperor Charles V./J.Chapman sculp.t./ London Published as the Act directs June 20th, 1807 by J.W.Wilkes. Bust in oval looking left; prostrated warrior under portrait. Stipple-engraving. 16.3 x 11.3 cm.
  - 0738. Karl X, Gustaf, king of Sweden, 1622-1660 (Flat-box 6, Folder 6)